Guide to the Hobart D. Myrick Papers 1901-1970
Montana State University-Bozeman Library
Hobart D. Myrick Papers
1901-1970
Montana State University Library, Merrill G. Burlingame Special Collections P.O. Box 173320 Bozeman, MT 59717-3320 United States Phone (406) 994-4242 Fax (406) 994-2851 http://www.lib.montana.edu/archives/ University Archivist spcoll@www.lib.montana.edu
Collection 2111, MtBC, us
Myrick, Hobart D. (Hobart Delaney), 1879-1973
2 linear feet
The Hobart D. Myrick Papers consists of documents pertaining to the operation of Myrick's ranch at Square Butte, Montana, personal correspondence, Myrick family genealogy, and various Geraldine, Montana institutions such as the Methodist Church, Equity Cooperative Association, and Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association. Also included are detailed financial records pertaining to Myrick's creation and presidency of the Square Butte Elevator Company.
Biographical Note
Hobart D. Myrick was born in Martelle, Iowa in 1879. He moved to Montana in 1909 with his wife, Mabel, and in 1911 took up residence at his homestead in Square Butte. While living in Square Butte, Myrick established the Square Butte Elevator Company and served as the company's president for 20 years. He served as a financial officer for the Methodist Church in nearby Geraldine, was a part of the Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, and had some interest in the Equity Cooperative Association. In 1950, Myrick moved to Bozeman, Montana where he would reside until his death in December of 1973.
This collection is organized into two series, the first dealing with the operation of Myrick's ranch at Square Butte, Montana. In addition to some personal correspondence series one also includes records dealing with Myrick family genealogy, and various Geraldine, Montana institutions such as the Methodist Church, Equity Cooperative Association, and Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association. Series two includes very detailed financial records pertaining to Myrick's creation and presidency of the Square Butte Elevator Company.
Series 1 Ranch and Personal Papers, 1901-1970
Series 2 Square Butte Elevator Company Records, 1929-1944
This collection is open for research.
Records and papers created or collected by H. D. Myrick were given to the MSU Libraries by Dr. Dana Myrick of Bozeman, MT in November of 1972.
Myrick, Hobart D. (Hobart Delaney), 1879-1973-Archives
Merrick family; Myrick family
Community Methodist Church (Geraldine, Mont.); Equity Cooperative Association (Geraldine, Mont.); Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association (Geraldine, Mont.); Square Butte Elevator Company (Square Butte, Mont.)
Geraldine (Mont.)-Church history; Square Butte (Mont.: Town)
Agriculture, Cooperative-Montana-Geraldine; Grain elevators-Montana-Square Butte (Town); Grain-Cooperative marketing-Montana-Geraldine; Methodist Church-Montana-Geraldine; Ranches-Montana-Square Butte (Town)
Personal papers-Montana-Square Butte (Town); Business records-Montana-Square Butte (Town); Church records and registers-Montana-Geraldine
Businessmen-Montana-Square Butte (Town); Ranchers-Montana-Square Butte (Town)
Agriculture; Ranching; Religion; Montana
- Ranch and Personal Papers, 1901-1970; Series 1
  Series 1 covers the personal and some business interests of H.D. Myrick. Included are ledgers, cards, and inventory books that cover almost every aspect of the ranch's operation. Also found in this series are more limited collections of Myrick's interests including his involvement with a number of other organizations: financial records from the Methodist Church of Geraldine, stock and correspondence regarding the Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association, and ledgers from the Equity Cooperative Association. There is little personal correspondence in this collection, but included are letters to and from James C. Zanto, the man Myrick leased his ranch to when he moved to Bozeman. This series is arranged with ranch papers, personal finance, personal correspondence, and genealogy files preceding those dealing with the Farmer's Union Grain Terminal Association and the Equity Cooperative Association.
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1926-1930 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1936-1941 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1945-1950 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Ranch Activity Ledger, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Annual Statements, 1901-1913 (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Annual Statements, 1914-1929 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Annual Statements, 1929-1942 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Inventory Book, 1937-1944 (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Bond and Miscellaneous Ledger, 1941-1965 (Box-folder 3/5)
  - H.D. Myrick Land Purchased in Fergus County, 1911 (Box-folder 3/6)
  - H.D. Myrick Ranch Profits, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 3/7)
  - H.D. Myrick Lease of Ranch to James C. Zanto, 1969 (Box-folder 3/8)
  - H.D. Myrick Correspondence: Letter to James C. Zanto, Eberhard Myrick, 1969 (Box-folder 3/9)
  - H.D. Myrick Correspondence: Letters Received from James C. Zanto, 1969 (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Myrick, Charles Theodore and Theresa Peet Myrick Family Tree (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Community Methodist Church of Geraldine, Montana Financial Papers, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 3/12)
  - Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association: Stock and Correspondence, 1939-1944 (Box-folder 3/13)
  - Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association: Stock and Correspondence, 1939-1944 (Box-folder 3/14)
  - Equity Cooperative Association of Geraldine, Montana: Ledgers, 1934-1944 (Box-folder 3/15-18)
  - Financial Activity Cards, 1908-1965 (Box 4)
  - Financial Activity Cards, 1908-1965 (Box 5)
- Square Butte Elevator Company Records, 1929-1944; Series 2
  Series 2 of the Myrick Papers deals exclusively with the Square Butte Elevator Company, a business Myrick founded and served as president until its incorporation into the Cooperative Elevator of Square Butte. Included are ledgers, audit reports, articles of incorporation and other information on the company and its employees. When the Square Butte Elevator Company was absorbed into the Cooperative Elevator of Square Butte, Myrick maintained both stock and interest in the new company so there are some pieces dealing with the new Cooperative. The contents of this series are arranged primarily in chronological order across two boxes to show the progression of the company up until it was absorbed into the Co-op.
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Audit Reports, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Audit Reports, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Audit Reports, 1935-1936; 1938 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Audit Reports, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Audit Reports, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Minutes of Proceedings, 1928-1946 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Ledger, 1931-1941 (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Social Security Info, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Miscellaneous Financial Records, 1938-1946 (Box-folder 7/1-2)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Proxies and Receipts for Stock Sold, 1944 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Stock Certificates, 1944 (Box-folder 7/4-6)
  - Square Butte Elevator Company Reorganization, 1944 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Cooperative Elevator of Square Butte Income Tax Papers, 1944 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Cooperative Elevator of Square Butte By-Laws, Instruction for Organization, Minutes of Proceedings (1st meeting), 1944 (Box-folder 7/9)